# Mayank Gupta



#### **PROFILE**

Experienced in data science internship at Corizo and as a senior researcher at IDYIA, showcasing adaptability and analytical skills. Actively involved in extracurricular activities as a core member of the SST Ted Talk Tribe. Currently pursuing a combined BSc + MSc program at Scaler School of Technology, affliated with BITS Pilani, with a perfect score of 100 in Computer Science in the CBSE 12th board exam, placing in the top 1% nationwide.

### **CONTACT DETAILS**

- Personal Websitemayank1365@gmail.com
- +91 9606036429
- 🕏 github.com/mayank1365
- @ linkedin.com/Mayank-Gupta

### **LANGUAGES**

- Java, Java Spring Boot
- MySQL, Python and Python Libraries
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Node.js, Express.js

#### SKILLS & INTERESTS

Backend Development
Statistical Data Analysis & Data
Visualization
Machine Learning

## **INTERNSHIPS & PROJECTS**

#### DATA SCIENCE INTERN at Corizo - Certificate

- Implemented effective data pre-processing methods using techniques such as normalization, scaling, feature selection, dimensionality reduction, and handling categorical data.
- Onducted statistical analyses and created impactful data visualizations.
- Enhanced data wrangling techniques often tackle real-world data challenges such as handling missing data, data transformation, cleaning, outlier detection, integration, time series handling, and feature engineering.

### YOUTUBE COMMENTS SCRAPER - Project Link

- ⋄ Scrapes comments from a YouTube video, converts them into vector embeddings using a pre-trained Sentence Transformer model.
- ♦ Stored these embeddings in a FAISS index in text format for efficient vector-based similarity search, by using Python via Jupyter notebooks.

### VEHICLE SERVICE MANAGEMENT - Project Link

Developed a comprehensive backend system for scheduling, maintaining, and tracking vehicle services, including CRUD operations for vehicles, services, and service providers, using Java and the Java Spring Boot framework, along with third-party applications like Postman and FakeStore.

### QUIZ WEBSITE - Website Link

Built a static website using HTML, CSS & JavaScript for 10 multiple choice GK questions that appear in randomized order, and calculate and display the final score.

### CASE STUDY ON YULU - Project Link

- Performed a study on YULU company data using Google Colab and Python libraries such as Pandas, NumPy, and Matplotlib for data cleaning and analysis.
- ♦ Identified the variables significant in predicting the demand for and the impact of electric cycles in the Indian market.

#### CUSTOMER DATA ANALYSIS OF AEROFIT - Project Link

- Identified customer characteristics based on the products purchased.
- ♦ Provided insights & recommendations on the business impact of the above.

### **EDUCATION**

### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE + MASTER OF SCIENCE

Scalar School of Technology, with Birla Institute of Technology and Science **2023–Present** 

⋄ Computer Science Major

10TH + 12TH, HIGH SCHOOL BGS National Public School (CBSE)

2019-2023

- ♦ 90% in 12th
- ♦ 9 CGPA in 10th

### **EXPERIENCES**

### CORE MEMBER, Ted Talk Tribe @ SST

Jan 2024-Present

Managing the logistics of the college newsletter, ensuring smooth coordination of scheduling and participant engagement in various club activities as a core member.

#### SENIOR RESEARCHER, IDYIA

Aug 2022-Feb 2023

 Researched and curated content on topics spanning several domains aiming to educate through social media.